

ANUPAMA

UI ENGINEER

anupamahosad.com



anuhosad@gmail.com



9242041508

WORK EXPERIENCE

Technical Lead - UI

Unbxd Sept 2017 - Today

Product Information Management System (PIM)

Built the Unbxd Product Information Management (PIM) system from scratch. PIM is a tool for e-commerce brands & retailers where they can efficiently manage all product related content at one place of instant familiarity with seamless distribution in the right format to various channels. Was responsible for the complete lifecycle of the UI portal right from choosing the UI technology, setting up the code base & build lifecycles to enforcing best practices. Built many reusable components that were used throughout the application which helped in building new features quickly.

Technical Lead - UI

Inmobi

Jan 2016 - Sept 2017

Inmobi Customer Interface Portal

The Inmobi Customer Interface Portal provides a platform for publishers and advertisers to come onboard and advertise/monetize with InMobi. Contributed in building various pages in this portal. As a tech lead I was responsible for delivering all the UI projects for the Performance App Download section on the customer interface portal. As part of this worked on creative manager which is a tool to simplify operations around creatives.

Senior Engineer - UI

Inmobi

Jan 2015 - Dec 2016

Reseller Platform

Contributed in building the campaign creation workflows in the Reseller Platform. As part of this built the creation flows for Banner, Interstitial and Video adformats.

ABOUT ME

UI Engineer with over 9+ years of experience in using client side technologies like HTML, CSS, JavaScript and libraries / frameworks like jQuery, Backbone, React, Handlebars JS, Underscore, Require JS, Node JS, Bootstrap, Less, Grunt and Webpack for building highly performant and scalable web applications. Having an extraordinary ability to go to details, I take complete ownership in solving any problem and build a deep understanding of the products I work on. I have also mentored and ramped up team members in various projects.

TECH SKILLS

HTML CSS Javascript Node JS JQuery
Handlebars.js Backbone JS React JS Gatsby
Less SCSS Grunt Webpack

EDUCATION

PES School Of Engineering (2008 - 2012) 81.28%

(Bachelor Of Engineering)

St Francis Composite PU college (2006 - 87.66% 2008)

(Pre University Course)

Mary Immaculate High School (1996 - 84.8% 2006)

(Secondary School Education)

Video Interstitial Ads

Worked on building video ads and explored solutions for prebuffering videos for a buffer free instant play experience that helped in improving the render rates and play rates significantly. Worked on implementing VAST and VPAID mobile video technologies. Also implemented viewability tracking in the video ads through Moat and IAS integrations.

AdFormats

Worked on the creation of cutting edge AdFormats like Banner Ads, Static Interstitial Ads, Frame Ads, Enriched Interstitial Ads and Carousal Ads. Automated the ad generation process using Grunt task runner that improved the efficiency of the deliverables.

Software Engineer - UI

Inmobi

June 2012 - Dec 2014

InMobi Lifetime Value Platform Portal

Contributed in building the InMobi Lifetime Value Platform Portal (LTVP). LTVP is a one stop shop for Mobile App Developers to analyze, monetize, and drive engagement for their Apps.

App Intelligence Portal Rich UI

Redesigned the App Intelligence Insights portal as part of Bootcamp Project. The main idea was to create a dashboard for the developer where they can view all the required information in brief at one place. The application used various widgets to display all the data visually.